I always think of brand and the ultimate
goal of brand as being a way to build
love with people so that they're, you
know, willing to grow the extra mile for
you and that they're willing to kind of
share similar passions for for you and
your product. And that's something that
you really can't get with like a $5 CPI.
>> Hello, I'm your host, David Bernard.
Today's conversation is shorter than
usual and will be featured in Revenue
Cat's state of subscription apps report.
Each episode in this series will explore
one crucial topic and share actionable
insights from top subscription app
operators. With me today, Lissa
Morimoto, senior growth manager working
on special projects at Photo Room. On
the podcast, I talk with Lissa about
breaking free from the paid acquisition
treadmill, how to repurpose offline
events into millions of online
impressions, and why a celebrity
partnership can go viral but still
completely flop. Hey, Lissa, thanks so
much for joining me on the podcast.
>> Thanks so much for having me, David.
>> So, I was really excited to have you on.
You've been doing some really creative,
interesting things at Photo Room and
we've talked so much about meta ads and
Tik Tok and organic and influencer and
all the things you can do with
marketing. You know, we've talked
endlessly about it on the podcast, but
there's just so many other ways to get
people's attention. And I think a lot of
apps, especially as they scale, are
starting to look at some of these more
traditional marketing channels that you
wouldn't think of for digital, but that
can actually be super effective and and
can really even compound your digital
spend. So, I wanted to talk today
specifically about offline, about actual
in-person marketing. So, let's talk
about these offline experiences and why
do that? Why as a digital company, a
photo room, are you doing these offline
marketing experiments? So, Footer Room
is a mobile app. We're also web app and
we have an API. And we've grown
significantly since 2019. So, we were
able to scale to almost 300 million
downloads um across a variety of
different you know methods. And I think
we I mean like most apps, we relied a
lot on paid acquisition for our growth,
especially the initial stages where you
know we were still testing a lot of
things out. We found product market fit
really early on as well and paid really
helped us scale that. Um but after a
while once you've grown so much through
paid channels you start experiencing
similar patterns. So you start seeing
things like ad fatigue you start seeing
that your campaigns aren't performing as
well. CPAs might you know go up
especially nowadays where everybody is
trying to crack digital acquisition. you
need to be, you know, creative in in
some way or another because your next
10,000 customers are probably not going
to come from Meta or any other, you
know, acquisition channel or digital
acquisition channel if you haven't been
able to to see success so far. And so I
selfidentify as somebody who's
chronically online, like it's in my
LinkedIn bio. It's, you know, my
personality and I I love all things, you
know, consumer marketing as well. So I
take a lot of inspiration from that
whether it's in the form of brand trips
that makeup companies do and and a lot
of other you know consumer consumer
oriented ways of marketing and the
reality is that we're all living in the
attention economy. So everybody's trying
to get your attention. We're fighting
for people's attentions. We're paying
for their attention and offline
marketing is just something that helps
crack and create memory. Um, and if your
digital app where you've relied so much
on paid acquisition, if you're if 70% of
your marketing budget is concentrated in
a single channel, you're likely already
putting your growth at risk because if
one thing happens to that channel, then
you have no other way of getting back.
It's kind of like a treadmill. The
treadmill's on, you're probably going to
be growing, but if your treadmill's off,
there's nowhere for you to go. And so,
we were able to scale to, you know, over
50 million AR using paid as our main
source of growth. Um, and this is public
information. I double checked and it was
something that my manager Juvier at the
time used to say all the time, you know,
like we need to capture people where
they are and they're probably on the
streets. They're probably in markets and
restaurants and thrift shops. And so
there's there's this beauty of on of
offline where you're meeting people
where they are and then helping them
remember you as you know a human and not
just a SAS product. Uh, because people
do tend to remember humans more. So, now
that you've been experimenting with
this, and we'll get to a couple of
examples to put this more concretely for
folks, but what are some of the the
things you've learned as far as like how
to be successful, what to measure, just
how do you think about these
non-traditional advertising
opportunities for an app? I always think
of brand and the ultimate goal of brand
as being a way to build love with people
so that they're, you know, willing to
grow the extra mile for you. Um, and
that they're willing to kind of share, I
guess, similar passions for for you and
your product. And that's something that
you really can't get with like a $5 CPI.
And so, Fod Room is a very datadriven
company and it's been so hard to find
kind of the right measurement, you know,
framework for it, especially because
traditionally if you're running a brand
campaign, you're likely trying to tie it
to the regular growth metrics that we
follow. So whether it's installs,
whether it's conversions, whether it's
retention and for us, I guess the moment
really cracked when we stopped looking
at brand from that perspective and we
really looked at love and how can we
really, you know, build this
relationship with our potential users.
And so the issue that we had before when
whenever we would try to do kind of
brand related campaigns is that we would
always compare maybe CPAs to what we
were spending on paid acquisition. And
that was really impacting our creativity
because we were always so limited in the
in the channels that we would explore.
So we were very focused on you know
influencers and cracking the infamous
Tik Tok ambassador playbook which did
work for us for a while but after you
know after a bit you start seeing that
everybody else is doing the same things
and there's no innovation there's no
creativity and for us our creativity was
unlocked when we decided to look at it
from the perspective of love. Right now
we measure brand uplift through branded
search. We run brand awareness surveys
and we look at very qualitative ways of
measuring instead of the traditional
growth framework that we normally would
look at it from.
>> It's tough because you know a lot of
people listening will be like well
that's nice for you. It is a privileged
position in a way to be at a company
where you can spend marketing dollars
where you're not tying as directly. But
that's the thing is that when you get to
that point and and I think even smaller
apps can find ways to do it on the
cheap. like it doesn't have to be super
expensive. It doesn't have to cost a lot
of time. And again, we're going to share
some examples of offline campaigns that
you've done. I think it's just so
important to be able to invest in the
company in this way and then creativity
in this way. And then those kind of
things can lead to new formats, new ads,
repurposing assets from the things that
you did. Like there is a lot of benefit
in the long run to thinking this way and
experimenting this way, but nearly
impossible to actually measure. And so
if if you're a company who has to get
that like dollar for-doll return, then
maybe this is not the thing for you, but
it can be so rewarding in the long run.
So I did want to put things in more
concrete terms for folks of some of the
campaigns that you've run. And so I know
one of the more interesting ones you ran
recently was an offline campaign in
London where you did a bunch of stuff in
person. What What was that?
>> Yeah, it's funny that you mentioned it
being a privilege because you're you're
so right. like I'm definitely in a
privileged position where we have kind
of resources to spend and it kind of
takes me back to when this campaign
originated. So I I worked on this
campaign with one of my best friends and
colleagues, Aisha, and I'm very proud to
call her a colleague and friend. And
this all started because I was sitting
on the couch with Aisha and all of a
sudden my CFO walks in and we jokingly
asked him like, "Hey, what would happen
if you, you know, just gave us a million
dollars for a campaign?" And I kind of
expected him initially to be like,
"Haha, like that's a really funny joke."
But he did take it seriously and you
know we started talking the three of us
we started brainstorming ideas and
obviously I didn't spend a million
dollars in my campaign but you know just
to give you an idea of of how this all
worked out and that's kind of how the
origin story of the campaign came up
because our initial mission was to help
people perceive photo room as more than
just a background remover. So, like I
said earlier, we found our initial
product market fit through our
background remover software, but then
now we've gotten to the point where we
have so many other tools to help people
selling goods online actually maximize
their chances of conversions that we
didn't have a way to a clear way of
showcasing it. And so, this campaign
started out with that kind of seed and
it eventually grew into something that
we could never have imagined it grown
to. And so, what we ended up doing is we
found a smaller market to test in
because we really wanted to have as much
raw data as possible. Um, and so that
was the UK, specifically London, where
we rented out kind of high footfall
traffic places that we could find that
had kind of a physical screen. And what
we really knew that we wanted to do was
we wanted to showcase the power of photo
room. So, we wanted to bring all of
these different tools to life, whether
it was in the form of a digital
activation or anything physical that
people could experience because, like I
said earlier, people really do resonate
more with your brand if they can see
humans working on it. Especially in the
age of AI, we've we're a very AIdriven
project. So, it's always been important
for us to have that human touch. And
what we ended up doing is we rented out
kind of these huge LED screens so that
people could walk in, they could
experiment the photo room photo booth,
so they would take pictures of
themselves, they could edit their
pictures, and then their images would
get blown up on this huge screen. That
ended up resulting in was a lot of
userenerated content. That's my biggest
tip for anybody trying to go offline
that you always have to factor in UGC or
online distribution to maximize your
chances of return especially of ROI. And
what ended up happening was that we had
15,000 people walk by this billboard.
They were able to experience Photo Room,
see pictures of other people on the
screens, and it was such an amazing
moment to not only connect with future
users of Photo Room, but also to
existing users. So we had people coming
in from, you know, Manchester to try out
the photo room photo booth. We had
people walking by who walked up to us
and said, "Really? Like AI can do this?"
And for us that was so rewarding to be
able to, you know, really have these
interactions with people. So yeah, in
the end it was amazing.
>> You mentioned repurposing some of the
content that you created there. So I
imagine you had like a small film crew
or somebody with an iPhone going around
taking video. Were there any particular
wins from that like you know I mean it's
just such a powerful thing to and it's
not the standard UGC just like
influencer with a selfie cam kind of
thing where you have like photo room
blown up on a billboard you have like
people really reacting excitedly. How
did the assets from that perform and
were there any kind of standouts from
that experiment?
>> So we actually had over 4 million views
on our collected UGC campaigns. So what
we ended up doing is we brought our
three ad creatives to the outer net and
so they were also there with us on the
day of the campaign and they recorded so
much content that they were able to
repurpose for ads and socials and you
know even LinkedIn. Uh I never would
have thought that LinkedIn would be kind
of a UGC first channel in the same way
that Tik Tok is. But we threw some Tik
Toks on on LinkedIn and it went I mean
it didn't go viral but we got way more
engagement than we expected. But yeah, I
think just having those 4 million
impressions in addition to the 15,000
people that we were able to interact
with was such a win and it really showed
us that when I mean it kind of made us
feel bigger than we actually were at the
time because you know we had people
commenting and and even messaging us
asking about how the how the campaign
went that it was so rewarding for
everybody involved. One of our biggest
wins I would say was getting coverage on
campaign magazine which is one of the
biggest publications for anybody doing
offline campaigns. they have, you know,
250,000 monthly visitors. So, I think
that was such such a rewarding
experience.
>> Yeah. And then with the partnerships
that y'all do, y'all did an incredible
partnership with like the Barbie movie
where you take a selfie and it removes
your background and puts you in the the
Barbie set or whatever. And so, what's
cool about your business is that getting
exposure in those kind of places
actually can drive future partnerships
and things like that. And that's another
thing I think folks don't think about is
that as you grow, there are
opportunities for partnerships. There's
just bigger opportunities that start to
come along and your standard like
digital advertising where you're just
going after your exact customer profile
and somebody's going to download the
app. That matters most early on, but as
you grow and there's bigger
opportunities, getting in front of
creatives outside the industry and other
things can provide tons of benefits.
It's fascinating how you were able to
land in that campaign magazine and and
I'm sure that that got in front of the
kind of people that you would
potentially partner with or hire or, you
know, do other things with. So, that's
such a great example. And then there was
another one you did in Japan. Tell me
about that one.
>> Yeah. Um, I mean, just to follow up on
the ICP on targeting your ideal customer
profile, I I try not to use acronyms, so
it's so hard, but our ICPs are
essentially small businesses. So,
anybody who's trying to sell online, and
for us, I mean, we also kind of go into
with the mentality that yes, you're a
business owner, but you're also consumer
first because you're likely already on
Instagram, you're likely already on Tik
Tok, you're likely already existing in
these spaces. And that's also why
whenever we run, you know, paid
acquisition, we don't even try to
optimize our creatives fully for
businesses. We try to have a fun twist
to it because ultimately consumers can
also be businesses. And when we tried
applying that mentality to a campaign
that we ran in Japan, it actually ended
up backfiring in the most interesting
way possible. So Japan is also a pretty
big market for photo room. And what we
ended up doing is we secured a
partnership with Tama specifically
because a lot of our user base in Japan
are also collectors. So that's a huge
market. If anybody has an app in in the
collector industry, Japan is definitely
where you should be. And what we ended
up doing is we ended up partnering with
Tamilia to host a community event in
their new offices that they opened up I
believe a year or two ago and they
wanted to increase the traffic to their
store. And so what we did is that our
team in Japan, they actually reached out
to a local comedian Kimuri who's
potentially the equivalent of Pete
Davidson in Japan to go in and host this
event. But what we didn't optimize for
was the actual foot traffic. And this
was before the London campaign, by the
way. So, we took all these learnings and
we keep on iterating, but we didn't
optimize for foot traffic specifically
because Kimuri's profile was very, very
discreet and he didn't want anybody that
he didn't know in the audience to
randomly show up and potentially
interact with him. And so, we kept it
very, very limited to journalists and
press. And we thought, okay, well, if
we're already thinking about online
distribution, then why not make it fully
about online distribution? And so we
relied 100% on press and journalists and
TV coverage to maximize your chances of
exposure. But since Kimuri has never a
sold online and b doesn't have a
conventional business, his audience did
not care about what we were doing. So
what they were focused on was the comedy
aspect. And of course like it doesn't
mean that they don't care about photo
room or that they don't know what photo
room you know does. But we didn't see
any uplift from the kamir campaign.
Whereas in London we saw an 18% uplift
in branded search for example. So for
us, I mean, it was shocking that we
didn't move the needle. Um, and that was
a huge learning and a very expensive
learning to to have made. If you're
going to try this strategy out, please,
please, please at least focus somewhat
on your ICP or make it a very wide
consumer event.
>> We talk about channel product fit and uh
and and things like that. It's so funny
to think about, you know, as you're
trying to get attention, you do need to
get attention with at least some kind of
audience that's that's going to be at
least tangentally related. And and you
know, great example is, you know, apps
all the time, you know, want to get
featured in the big tech publications or
other places, but a lot of times those
don't end up driving much download
because like people reading Techrunch,
it's like they don't care about your
app. They're not reading TechCrunch to
find out about the new apps. That was a
decade ago, right? And so it is funny
that by hiring a comedian, you got a lot
of attention and it's great to like
brainstorm ways to get that kind of
attention, but that you do still need to
kind of figure out the scope of that
attention and figure out ways to kind of
lean it toward people who are actually
going to care and people who are going
to engage with Photo Room.
>> For sure. I was talking to somebody who
used to work at Comm and Comm did a lot
of celebrity partnerships back in the
days. I think they still do today. And I
remember asking them like, "Oh, but you
partnered with LeBron James. Like that
was so cool." And they were like, "Yeah,
we did, but actually that ended up being
our most expensive campaign and our
worst performing campaign because LeBron
James' audience actually does not care
about getting better sleep. They care
about basketball." But that was a huge
learning as well. And I think I wish I
had heard that before the Kamuri
campaign came out.
>> Yeah, that's such a great example. Well,
this has been so much fun. As we wrap
up, anything you wanted to shout out?
Any job openings on your team or
anything like that?
>> Yeah. Um, I just want to shout out Aisha
and Ka who are my, you know, my go-tos
when it comes to anything brand campaign
related. We have a new one coming out in
May, so very excited for that. It's
going to be in New York. and we're
hiring for a lot of positions. So, check
out our website and you can stay in
touch through LinkedIn or any other
social media platform that you can find
me on.
>> Awesome. Thank you much for joining me.
>> Yeah, thanks so much, David.
>> Thanks so much for listening. If you
have a minute, please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.